{
    "id": "d78323b0055142569f458315e40f80c9",
    "title": "Infinitive or Ing Form Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "f298c18ff1ff445892b3a6e13bd161cb",
            "title": "Ing Form or Infinitive",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I wouldn't .................................. a loan.",
                    "description": "After advise, we use an ing form, if there is no object. If there is an object, we use an infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "advise to take",
                        "advise taking",
                        "advise you to take"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We don't allow ......................... in the kitchen.",
                    "description": "After allow we use an ing form if there is no object. If there is an object, we use an infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "smoking",
                        "to smoke",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Guests are not allowed ............................ in the kitchen.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "smoking",
                        "to smoke",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are proud ................................",
                    "description": "The adjective proud can be followed by either an -ing form or an infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to have won",
                        "of having won",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I tried ..................... the wheel, but my hands were stiff.",
                    "description": "After try, we can use either an infinitive or an -ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "changing",
                        "to change",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would like .............................. you something.",
                    "description": "After would like, we use infinitives. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to tell",
                        "telling",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Do you like .............................?",
                    "description": "We use an -ing form after like to make a general statement or to ask a general question about preferences. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "dancing",
                        "to dance",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I slowly began ................................. what she said.",
                    "description": "The verbs understand, realise and know are not normally used in the continuous form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "understanding",
                        "to understand",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am sorry .................................. my temper this morning.",
                    "description": "Sorry about + ing is used to refer to past things one regrets. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to lose",
                        "about losing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not afraid ............................... the truth.",
                    "description": "There is little or no difference between afraid of + ing or afraid + infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "of telling",
                        "to tell",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Sorry ............................ you waiting. We can start now.",
                    "description": "Sorry + infinitive is used to apologize for current situations. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to keep",
                        "for keeping",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I hate .............................. on weekends.",
                    "description": "After hate, both infinitives and ing forms can be used. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to work",
                        "working",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}